export const GOVERNMENTA2007 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. A major characteristics of a government is",
A: "anonymity",
B: "resistance",
C: "sovereignty",
D: "homogeneity",
answer: "C. sovereignty",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. Democracy means a system of government in which",
A: "the minority rules",
B: "different views are accommodated.",
C: "highly qualified people rule",
D: "there is no opposition",
answer: "B. different views are accommodated.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. Feudalism is system of government in which the",
A: "parliament controls the land",
B: "vassals control the land",
C: "state controls and land",
D: "Lords control the land",
answer: "D. Lords control the land",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. A necessary condition for the rule of law is the existence of",
A: "a special tribunal",
B: "an independent judiciary",
C: "supremacy of the president",
D: "legislative body",
answer: "B. an independent judiciary",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. Public bills are initiated by",
A: "Executive",
B: "legislature",
C: "judiciary",
D: "electorates",
answer: "B. legislature",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. Apart from law-making, the legislature also",
A: "checks the executive and controls the treasury",
B: "controls delegated powers and appoints Chief Directors",
C: "exercises judicial powers and the elects the President",
D: "appoints judges and removes cabinet ministers",
answer: "A. checks the executive and controls the treasury",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. In a federation, matters in the concurrent list are under the jurisdiction of",
A: "both and federal and state government",
B: "the federal government only",
C: "the state governments only",
D: "local government authorities",
answer: "A. both and federal and state government",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. Which of the following is not a condition for the establishment of a unitary state?",
A: "small size",
B: "low population",
C: "limited resources",
D: "geographical proximity",
answer: "D. geographical proximity (Geographical proximity can actually favor a unitary state.)",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Which of the following countries in West Africa formed a confederation?",
A: "Guinea and Ghana",
B: "Liberia and Burkina Faso",
C: "Senegal and The Gambia",
D: "Guinea and Senegal",
answer: "C. Senegal and The Gambia (They formed the Senegambia Confederation.)",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. In a confederal system of government, ultimate power resides in the",
A: "executive President",
B: "prime minister",
C: "central government",
D: "constituent governments",
answer: "D. constituent governments",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. In a parliamentary system of government, the ministers are nominated from",
A: "pressure groups",
B: "the legislature",
C: "practicing lawyers",
D: "experienced civil servants",
answer: "B. the legislature",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. A constitutional power given to an autonomous body to discharge specific functions is known as a",
A: "delegated authority",
B: "separation of powers",
C: "rule of law",
D: "judicial review",
answer: "A. delegated authority",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. A chief executive, who is both the head of state and the head of government is called the",
A: "Prime Minister",
B: "Presiding Member",
C: "Governor-General",
D: "President",
answer: "D. President",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. In a monarchy, succession to the throne is",
A: "voluntary",
B: "hereditary",
C: "selective",
D: "elective",
answer: "B. hereditary",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. One of the sources of revenue for local government councils is",
A: "excise duties",
B: "import duties",
C: "value added tax",
D: "market tolls",
answer: "D. market tolls",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. A bicephalous executive exists in a",
A: "presidential system of government",
B: "parliamentary system of government",
C: "fixed by parliament",
D: "determined by the Judicial Council",
answer: "B. parliamentary system of government",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. To preserve the independence of the judiciary, Judges salaries are normally",
A: "determined by the Head of State",
B: "charged on the consolidated fund",
C: "fixed by Parliament",
D: "determined by the Judicial Council",
answer: "B. charged on the consolidated fund",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. The head of the judiciary is known as the",
A: "Chief Justice",
B: "Minister of Justice",
C: "Director of Public Prosecution",
D: "Chief Magistrate",
answer: "A. Chief Justice",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. The central theme of fascism is that the",
A: "leader is above the law",
B: "the leader is subject to the constitution",
C: "government is limited by people’s power",
D: "individuals in the state have unlimited rights",
answer: "A. the leader is above the law",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. In which of the following ways can a citizen’s right be guaranteed in a state?",
A: "Entrenchment of individual’s rights in the constitution",
B: "Organizing periodic elections",
C: "Election of judges by the electorate",
D: "Setting up of public tribunals",
answer: "A. Entrenchment of individual’s rights in the constitution",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. The powers of the courts to nullify the actions of both the executive and the legislature is known as",
A: "impeachment",
B: "judicial review",
C: "judicial independence",
D: "separation of powers",
answer: "B. judicial review",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. One of the fundamental functions of political parties is to",
A: "determine government decisions",
B: "delimit constituency boundaries",
C: "appoint presiding officers for elections",
D: "select candidates for elections",
answer: "D. select candidates for elections",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. In a defacto one party system",
A: "no party is legally allowed to operate",
B: "other parties exist but only one party dominates",
C: "only the party in power stands for elections",
D: "no one party gains an overall majority",
answer: "B. other parties exist but only one party dominates",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. Which of the following countries operates a two-party system?",
A: "Australia",
B: "The Gambia",
C: "U.S.A.",
D: "Sierra Leone",
answer: "C. U.S.A.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. One of the advantages of the two-party system is that it",
A: "accelerates economic development",
B: "provides a relatively stable government",
C: "caters for the rich in the society",
D: "creates unity in parliament",
answer: "B. provides a relatively stable government",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. Coalition government is usually found in a",
A: "republican system",
B: "unitary system",
C: "multi-party system",
D: "fascist systems",
answer: "C. multi-party system",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. Franchise means the right",
A: "to free speech",
B: "to gainful employment",
C: "of citizens to vote and be voted for",
D: "to make laws in Parliament",
answer: "C. of citizens to vote and be voted for",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. Which of the following is not allowed to vote?",
A: "Labourers",
B: "Aliens",
C: "Lawyers",
D: "Students above 18 years",
answer: "B. Aliens (Generally, citizens of other countries do not have the right to vote in a foreign country's elections.)",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. A run-off elections is held when",
A: "no candidate wins the required majority",
B: "there are independent candidates only",
C: "there is no running mate",
D: "there is no opposition",
answer: "A. no candidate wins the required majority",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. The simple plurality system is also known as",
A: "proportional representation system",
B: "alternative vote",
C: "single transferable vote",
D: "first-past-the post system",
answer: "D. first-past-the post system",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. The main aim of a pressure group is to",
A: "organize non-formal education",
B: "influence government decisions",
C: "mobilize workers against government",
D: "put pressure on their members",
answer: "B. influence government decisions",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. Which of the following is a type of a pressure group?",
A: "The Legislature",
B: "The Military",
C: "The Senate",
D: "The Bar Association",
answer: "D. The Bar Association (An association of lawyers, it aims to influence legal and judicial matters.)",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. The idea of collective responsibility associated with the executive arm of Government implies that",
A: "a member of the executive can review the decisions of the cabinet",
B: "a member of the executive cannot answer questions in public",
C: "ministers are bound by all decisions made by the cabinet",
D: "cabinet is bound to resign for an unpopular policy",
answer: "C. ministers are bound by all decisions made by the cabinet",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. Private ownership of the means of production by the individual is the fundamental aim of",
A: "Totalitarianism",
B: "Feudalism",
C: "communism",
D: "capitalism",
answer: "D. capitalism",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. One of the functions of the Civil Service is to",
A: "advise ministers on policies",
B: "sit in parliament",
C: "appoint judges",
D: "determine government budget",
answer: "A. advise ministers on policies",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. All the following are features of the Civil Service except",
A: "anonymity",
B: "diplomacy",
C: "neutrality",
D: "permanence",
answer: "B. diplomacy (Diplomacy is primarily the function of the foreign service.)",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. Public corporations are administered by",
A: "Management Committee",
B: "Parliament",
C: "Board of Governors",
D: "Board of Directors",
answer: "D. Board of Directors",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. Local government bodies are established by",
A: "the judiciary",
B: "acts of parliament",
C: "city councils",
D: "the minister of local government",
answer: "B. acts of parliament",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. A major problem facing local governments in West Africa is",
A: "lack of equipment",
B: "inadequate funds for development",
C: "illiterate councillors",
D: "lack of motivation for revenue collectors",
answer: "B. inadequate funds for development",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. Which of the following West African countries was not a colony?",
A: "Nigeria",
B: "Liberia",
C: "The Gambia",
D: "Ghana",
answer: "B. Liberia",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. Diplomatic immunity is a limitation on",
A: "separation of powers",
B: "checks and balances",
C: "parliamentary privileges",
D: "rule of law",
answer: "D. rule of law",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. The head of the colonial administration in British West Africa was the",
A: "Governor",
B: "Officer commanding the troops",
C: "Queen",
D: "Colonial Secretary",
answer: "A. Governor",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. The main disadvantage of a military government is that",
A: "traditional rulers are ignored",
B: "manpower development is suspended",
C: "rights are trampled on",
D: "decision-making is slow",
answer: "C. rights are trampled on",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. A country in West Africa that operates a Federal System of government is",
A: "The Gambia",
B: "Nigeria",
C: "Sierra Leone",
D: "Ghana",
answer: "B. Nigeria",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. The two countries that jointly promoted the formation of ECOWAS were",
A: "Nigeria and Benin",
B: "Senegal and Ivory Coast",
C: "Togo and Ghana",
D: "Togo and Nigeria",
answer: "B. Senegal and Ivory Coast",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. The headquarters of the Organization of African Unity is in",
A: "Accra",
B: "Abuja",
C: "Tripoli",
D: "Addis Ababa",
answer: "D. Addis Ababa",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. Voting on behalf of another person is known as",
A: "quota system",
B: "electoral college",
C: "voting by proxy",
D: "transferable voting",
answer: "C. voting by proxy",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. According to Montesquieu, fusion of powers can lead to",
A: "arbitrariness",
B: "efficient government",
C: "stability in government",
D: "protection of individual liberties",
answer: "A. arbitrariness",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. A function of the International Court of Justice is to hear disputes between",
A: "a citizen and the government",
B: "the executive and the legislature",
C: "two presidents",
D: "sovereign states",
answer: "D. sovereign states",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. Public corporations are established with the major aim of",
A: "creating mass employment",
B: "competing with private enterprises",
C: "maximizing profits",
D: "rendering essential services",
answer: "D. rendering essential services",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},


]